Andrew Cotter

Computational Art + Design

Contact

thatcotter.github.io cotter.andrew.p@gmail.com

Personal Statement

I'm a constant learner. Each project is an opportunity towards discovering new tools and processes, as well as cultivating a new and better understanding of technology, and our relationship to it. I like to make things that have both physical and digital dimensions to them. In my work, I try to manifest the convergence of these two fields in the form of interactive installations, games, and wearable devices. I'm always looking at our relationships to technology and the ways we wield it: how it does things for us, and to us.

Core Competencies

Creative Coding

I approach writing code like writing poetry, focusing on the mechanics, the demystification of tools, and hacking the conventions of art-making with computation.

Design Research

The first step to solving a problem is understanding it. By interviewing end-users and testing prototypes, I can better understand what the solution is.

Professional Experience

Development Intern, Red Paper Heart Summer 2017

Worked in tangent with the design team to program/build interactive installations and experiences for commercial clients using openFrameworks, Cinder, and Arduino.

Development Intern, Cipher Prime Fall 2015 - Summer 2016

Assisting with design/development of video games and interactive media in various frameworks such as Unity, Cinder, and P5.js.

Interaction Developer, Night Kitchen Fall 2014 - Summer 2016

Leading design/development research by exploring new tools for the web and interactive installations and demonstrating implementations to the rest of the team.

Skills / Tools

Adept:

openFrameworks (C++)
Arduino / Physical Computing
Front-End Web (HTML/MD/SCSS/JS)
p5.js

Intermediate:

Cinder (C++)
Unity (C#)
Three.js (WebGL)
Node.js/Express/Socket.io/Electron
GLSL (Fragment Shaders)

Currently Learning:

Clojure/Clojurescript React.js reGL.js (WebGL) GLSL (Vert Shaders)

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant, Fall 2017
Immersive Storytelling, Parsons

Code Instructor, Summer 2017
MFA D+T Bootcamp, Parsons

Programming Tutor, Spring 2017
The New School Learning Center

Education / Honors

MFA Design + Technology

Parsons, Class of 2018 President of Dorkshop (2016-2017)

BS Industrial Design

University of the Arts, Class of 2014 President of Literary Society (2013-2014)

Achieved the rank of Eagle Scout

BSA Troop 139, 2010